Okay, the meeting has started. So, the
recording has started. I will admit
everybody uh who is in the waiting room.
Please remember while we are admitting
people, it does take a few minutes for
everybody to uh be admitted. So, uh we
will do go over that over the next
couple of minutes. In the meantime, just
to start things on off, my name for
those who are now in the room, uh my
name is Dominic Zerlo and I am the
director for the center for medical
cannabis and psilocybin here at New
Mexico Department of Health. And uh this
is the meeting for the dosage
administration and clinical practice
committee with Ian Dunn as the chair.
Just as a couple of reminders, we are
recording this meeting to be posted to
the website at a later time. And just as
a friendly reminder when speaking,
please remember to watch your language
and make sure that it is appropriate. So
we do not have to uh go back in and edit
or bleep anything uh that is
inappropriate um on the meeting. So if
we're talking about for example
different uh particular cultivars of
mushroom just please make sure uh that
if there is an inappropriate word in the
name refer to it by initials and that
would be fine. It is also the reason why
we do not have everybody on video um
because we want to ensure that we don't
have to exclude a video from public view
simply due to something in the
background being inappropriate. While
thankfully that has not happened with
any of the meetings regarding medical
psilocybin, it has happened in other
occasions and we just are trying to
ensure that we can avoid that. Um, in
addition, the other reason we do not
have everybody except for some of the
board members and staff members on
visual is because we recognize that in
some areas of the state, internet is not
necessarily as good as it is in other
areas and we want to ensure that uh
people are not dropped from the call
more often due to issues with the
bandwidth if everybody is on by video.
So, we do limit that somewhat. Um, and
so with that, uh, it looks like
everybody who is in the waiting room has
been admitted. So I will turn it on over
to you, Ian, for you to start the
meeting officially and move forward.
>> Good morning everyone. Uh, or not
morning anymore. Good afternoon
everyone. I appreciate you guys taking
the time to be here. Um, my name is Ian
Dunn. I am the chair of the dosage
administration clinical practice
committee and I'm here to um you know
help guide this along. Can we get to the
next slide?
So thank you again for um attending this
meeting. So what this meeting is serving
to do is looking at the community input
from last meeting on dosage levels.
While we already adopted the dosage
definitions, um those dosage levels are
important as well. So we're going to be
further discussing and uh looking into
what we can do for that.
Next slide. So again, just as a reminder
to everyone, committees operate in an
advisory capacity. They provide
individuals provide forum for
individuals who may be experts but may
not serve on the board due to real or
perceived conflicts of interest.
Committee support the board by expanding
community input incorporating subject
matter expertise and increasing
participation in program development.
All right. And then Jorge if you
wouldn't mind pulling up those community
input dosage categories.
Perfect.
And I've also provided it in the chat so
everyone has access to um the document.
But basically what I'm going over is
just the compilation of what we received
from the community um embalmed into
words. So we start with the mini dose.
This is equivalent to 1.4 to 5.6 6
milligrams of psilocybin um but
expressed in the MTP that we adopted
earlier. This range is known for mood
enhancement, sub subtle effective
brightening and no perceptual
distortion.
The thresh this would be usually for um
if we were introducing someone to
psilocybin who may have had anxiety
about experiences um or as an upramp to
the therapeutic doses. But um that's its
service point. Most uh psilocybin
research that I've read has had an
active placebo dose at 5 milligrams. So
this is within that range.
So I will now allow any discussion or
comments on um the mini dose category
whether it needs to be changed, updated
or just general thoughts.
And for anybody not sure on how to raise
your hand to speak, I have put those
instructions in the chat.
James, I see your hand is up.
I'm getting your microphone unmuted
here.
Okay, James, you are unmuted.
>> Afternoon everyone and Ian, uh, thank
you again for being the chair here. Um,
just a couple quick comments. I like
where we're sitting with this again, and
I'm assuming that this is just a
one-time dose, right? So,
the comments, but that's that's kind of
where I sit with this when I look at it
right now. And I I do like the
conversion and uh that that speaks to me
as far as what I've used and what we're
used to using in Oregon and stuff. It's
right there. I think we start with that.
So that's that's my thought. Thank you.
>> All righty. So with no other comments,
we will go ahead and go to talk about
the threshold psychedelic dose. Um this
is on the end where maybe the provider
or patient is having a little bit of
anxiety but not necessarily so that they
want to start at the lowest dose. Um
this is would produce mild euphoria,
early sensory amplification, subtle
visual enhancement. Um it's a very light
psychedelic dose, but it represents a
transition point from non- psychedelic,
not visually impacting to um much more
perceptible psychedelic effects.
It's dosage range is between 4 to 6.9
mtp roughly equal to 5.6 to 9.6
milligrams of psilocybin.
And I will now open to any comments,
questions, concerns on the threshold
dose.
All righty. With no comments, we can go
ahead and move on to what I would
consider the most mainstream of the
approaches. It is between 7 to 21.9
milligs of MTP.
Um,
it is a moderate psychedelic dose. It's
on the low end of this range. Colors
become more vivid um with some closed
and open eye visuals. On the high end,
patients may experience kaleidoscopic
visuals and mild visual disturbances.
This is a moderate to full psychedelic
experience. Um it overlaps with the most
commonly studied therapeutic dosage
ranges consistent with fixed dose
clinical trials demonstrating reliable
psilicin exposure and therapeutic
outcomes.
I will open any comment questions
concerns on the moderate psychedelic
dose.
All right, seeing none, we can go ahead
and move on to that highintensity
psychedelic dose. Chris has his hand up.
>> Oh, Chris
>> and Chris,
you are
>> Yeah, I just have um
maybe one I don't know wording thing.
Should we should we include the word
psychedelic in each of these doses or
should it just be mini dose, threshold
dose, moderate dose, um and a high
intense or and then going on to the next
one. uh a high dose.
I think intensity is relative based on
people's sensitivity and also whether
they're on SSRI that intensity might be
um mitigated by some of those effects.
But uh going back on these other ones
that just that that wording change
perhaps.
>> Yeah. Uh that actually sounds great. So
I went ahead and strike all of the
repetitive psychedelic from each of the
dosage and I appreciate your comment. I
also see James has his hand up.
>> Yeah. And just one comment was I I just
don't see administration length time. I
didn't know if we needed to add that
somewhere into here or what's your
thought on you know when you're doing
these doses. Let's say the I like the
moderate range. Um but are we going to
do a like for us a duration of action or
a length of we do see that in some of
the other states they're saying hey if
you do this dose it's going to last 4 to
6 hours or if you do the mini dose it
lasts this long is what's your thought
on that?
>> Um I actually agree that we need
different safety protocols for them. So,
I was um the reason that they're broken
up like this and not specifically
addressed here would be the so that we
could defer per the specific dosage
ranges what those safety issues were to
the patient safety and qualification
committee. Um
and then we would work there to adjust
things like um
how long they have to be in
administration, how long until you know
they are safe to operate a motor vehicle
and and questions like that. Um but in
terms of the specific doses um
that
could be included here, we could
definitely add it. Um, but in my head I
had deferred it to that committee.
>> Gregory Evans, your mic has been
unmuted.
Um, I'm curious why you're hitting 22
milligrams as the ceiling of the
moderate dose
as opposed to like 18, which would be
kind of your classic dose category. It's
not a challenge, just a curiosity.
Oh, so I had provided I always prefer to
provide a little bit of wiggle room in
the event that someone has, you know,
different gut biomes and other things
that are going to impact um the
absorption and things like that. So if
for say a facilitator they were
prescribed within a moderate dose, then
that facilitator could start them
and say, "Okay, after
x amount of time it still hasn't hit.
Well, we can still provide within the
dosage range. So, it was meant to be
more so a buffer than a full-on
set.
>> So, if I'm understanding you, it's like
say we're dealing with standard land
race potency of like 5 milligrams per
gram of or of let's talk insilocybin
equivalency for a minute. Um, just
because those numbers are com
commonly understood.
Um, so if you have a five and you go to
therapy and they say, "Hey, we're going
to give you five mill, we're going to
give you five grams." And you sit down
and in an hour you have an opportunity
to updose 2 grams. Is that what you're
saying?
>> That would be my expectation with this.
Um, that would of course impact things
like you would have to reset your
administration clock for when they would
be good. Um, but that was my original
idea. Not so much plan.
>> All right. Um, have you I mean how many
people in the room have done a dose that
high?
I see you, Chris.
Copy that. Yeah, I'm not challenging it.
I just think that we're a little bit
outside of standard scoping on that. Um,
but yeah, I yield.
>> So, yeah, and I would be okay with
setting that MTP down to 18 if that is
the consensus.
And then Jamie had
>> just want to be clear, I'm not
specifically asking for that.
>> Okay,
>> James, your mic has been enabled.
>> And Ian, just to circle back on that,
under each dose category, even if safety
determines that administration length of
time, I would just myself like to see it
added as a category um with like TBD or
something. Uh just a thought. I just
think it's important when people look at
this that that's in there as well. Um
because it's more encompassing. It's
just,
you know, it's just it kind of goes with
that right underneath clinical
interpretations, you know, type of type
of style for each one. But it could be,
you know, decided later again, but just
thoughts.
>> All right. Thank you.
And Gregory.
Greg, Gregory, your mic is enabled.
>> Interesting thought. Like I think I saw
Kate mention uh the leeway. What if
these ranges over overlapped, right?
Because there are so many variables in
dosage and and administrating
uh in specific context where it's like
you were saying it's like you know we
want the flexibility. So what if like
moderate dose went to 22 but then the
high dose started at 18. So like there's
overlap
con to consider the myid of variables
that go into deciding a dose for a
specific human.
I actually think that would be a great
idea to set the to allow overlap within
the ranges to accommodate the fact that
every person is going to process the
medicine a little bit differently and
that would help to do our best to
accommodate. So I would actually support
that heavily um if again that's what the
consensus is on.
I think it's worth exploring. I'll draw
a picture.
Uh Dominic.
>> Yeah. Good afternoon everybody. I just
um wanted to mention to remember that
for this particular committee and what's
kind of happening in here, very little
of this is actually going to be part of
the regulatory side. A lot of this is
going to end up being within the
guidelines
um and uh and and in the end a lot of it
will end up being up to the particular
practitioners facilitators
um to be able to make that. So these are
guidance and guidelines um not
necessarily going to be like for example
if a facilitator says you know somebody
is within that moderate dose range if
they're on the upper end you know that
they wouldn't necessarily go into that
high intensity. The guidelines are
really just to sort of create a little
bit of a structure for the facilitators
and practitioners to work off of as they
make those final determinations. Just as
for example, if you go to the doctor and
they're prescribing a medication, they
may have guidelines on how much to
prescribe, but for a particular
medication, but each individual case may
be a little bit different. And so, just
keep that in mind um when looking at it.
It doesn't necessarily need to be
something where we're saying this is,
you know, at um you know, a fine level
of this is what exactly happens in each
situation. They're just these are and I
don't mean that as just but these are
guidelines not hard fast in stone or
regulations or anything on that side. I
hope that helps and makes a little bit
more sense.
>> Yeah. And as another analogy when nurses
get orders from doctors they usually
come in a range. It's like if take this
first, if this doesn't work, then try
this. Or it'll say morphine 1 to 4
milligrams. um depending on the severity
of the pain. So definitely things like
that can um impact it. So I don't
that the facilitator needs a little bit
of leeway to to breathe and kind of do
their job is kind of where I was going
with that. But uh James had his hand up.
>> Ian, uh just a thought on this too just
to get clarity
with the moderate range and the high
range. Are we saying again that this is
a one administration session that this
facilitator um because again in Oregon
you know we're allowed to split that
dose right so let's say they get the 50
we could split it and then give it to
them both you know again this is based
off their safety plan and and what their
intention is on this stuff and again
with us it would be what their medical
you know pathway would be um and what
that intention would look like and that
safety plan would look like. But is this
going to be a is your is your thought is
your interpretation more of like a
splitting you know can they split it or
is it one dose let's say they they do
say oh I'll do the 36 and and even a
range let's say they say I want 40 um do
they get it all at once and then you
know do they have to come back for the
second let's say that you know that
second time you know are we allowed to
split it are we not allowed to split it
what's your thoughts on this stuff with
the dosing of dosing ranges.
>> In my head, we would be allowed to split
it. Um, if
the tests in order to determine
someone's gut microbiome are too
expensive to require from all patients.
Um, so unfortunately what we're going to
be left with is is a little bit of
ambiguity. And I think that being able
to split a dose um would be beneficial.
Then you could um prevent hopefully some
of the adverse instances like um bad
trips or whatever the more formal way of
saying that is um from happening then we
should definitely take those actions.
That's why I've given a little bit of a
buffer is to say, hey, don't go and give
all 21.9 milligrams if you're doing a
moderate dose out the gate. Save a
little bit. See what happens.
They're doing good. That's when we can
either say, well, they don't need the
rest. But if they're feeling very
minimal effects, then we can up it a
little bit still within a safe range.
But I do appreciate your input.
Um, Nathan,
Nathan, you've been uh your mic has been
enabled.
Uh just as a reminder, um it once we
enable your microphone from the
Department of Health site, you just need
to unmute. Oh, there you go, Nathan.
>> I figured out. Sorry, I'm not familiar
with Teams. Um so I just um want to make
sure um I'm kind of clear. So um the
prescriber will define a dose range that
can be used by the facilitator
and then um and then it's up to the
facilitator to decide kind of use their
judgment where where they want to use
that.
So we would be providing what dose
ranges can be recommended and then the
provider would pick a range and say this
person should probably get a moderate
dose. Um, and then it would be up to
that specific provider to say, "Okay,
well, let's start with
half of it or 3/4 reserve and then
dispense once we know kind of how
they're doing, ensuring that they're in
the right mindset and that we can
minimize adverse um, instances.
Great. Thank you.
Any
other hands
and Chris?
Um I'm sorry Ian. I'm not sure if we've
gotten to the high high dose yet. Um if
we haven't, I apologize, but this
appears to me that we're capping our
dose limit at some point. Is that the
case?
Yes. So, I had originally had um in our
last meeting a
dosage that just said um
I believe it was
I there was no maximum. It just said
above 50. Um and then overwhelmingly the
community input was to set that
established cap range at 50 mg of
psilocybin. Um so that's what is
included in this document.
>> So that's already been determined
through the committee that that cap
>> that cap has not been determined through
the committee. We have not had an
official vote on it. Um, but that was
what the community input had largely
said. So, I had included this document
is just an elomeration of what the
community had said and that's why we're
discussing it today.
Yeah, I I think I would
recommend that we not have a cap on it
because again with people that are
taking SSRIs might need much higher
doses to uh achieve the desired results.
Also, um I know from working with
veterans that some of them need to take
much larger doses than normal people to
kind of get the results that they need.
And so I would recommend that maybe
there be an increased safety plan or
some other um
some other method where people could
receive higher doses um perhaps with
extra screening.
>> Yeah, I do appreciate that. Um what I'm
going to go ahead and do is just read
out the highintensity dose because I
think that has um created a lot of
intrigue as well. that way we can have a
fuller um conversation on it. So the
ranges from 22 to 36 mtp roughly equal
to 36 to 50 milligrams of psilocybin.
It's intense sensory distortions market
alteration of self-reerential cognition
and increased likelihood of ego
dissolution. Um
and it is the upper range dosing
reported in depression, PTSD and
substance use disorder trials. So
that's just the current language. So I
will once again turn over to um whoever
would like to speak. Um Katie if you can
unmute.
>> Gregory you are next. You may unmute
yourself.
>> Thank you Katie. Thank you everyone.
Chris um I'm with um just going to
reiterate or kind of support that lane
of thinking. I'm I don't think I was
aware of the conversation where or like
any input
around capping at 50 and and I would
love to review that those conversations.
Um I'm very much
would uh
try to not regulate the top end. I mean,
what you're looking at here is like two
grams of of Zaps could easily exceed
that dosage. And you know, like there's
reasons people may want to get into that
zone.
Again, it's back into like the
therapist's discretion because we are in
this container, right? Like, but I I
would just very much not advise capping
it. everyone else, all the other states
seem to have done that for safety
reasons or whatever, but like those
models all
kind of they're different than ours. And
we have this really unique container
where we can experiment with very
um yeah, measurable
uh container where we can measure
things. So, I don't know. I'm with I'm
very much with Chris on that. So that's
all.
>> Nathan, you may unmute yourself.
>> Oh yeah, I arrived late so I I didn't
get introduced myself. I'm a psychiatry
resident at UNM and um other medications
don't have caps like this. So there's
some circumstances where um you'll end
up prescribing you'll need to prescribe
more of a medication than is what's um
you know FDA approved. Sometimes quite a
lot. Um so uh and what Chris is pointing
out is I think great concern. Um I don't
know if it being uh have any uh evidence
in the literature yet but anecdotally
yeah folks who are taking SSRIs often
times require like you know quite a bit
more not to get to a higher plane but
just to get to the same plane as
somebody who would uh same plane is not
on those SSRIs. And so, um, of course,
you need some kind of checks and
balances. And the way it works within
other medications is, you know, I'm free
to prescribe however much I want of of
whatever medication, but if there's a
bad outcome, then that gets investigated
and people come and they they they look
at, you know, the records and they say,
"Well, why did you give this guy, you
know, this much medication?"
Um, and so that's it's that kind of um
that that's that's what causes people to
be more careful. If you're with if you
have a bad outcome and you're within the
kind of recommended areas, so you could
just instead of having hard limits have
recommendations, then it's a lot harder
if there is an investigation for people
to say that you made a bad judgment. But
if you know uh if I'm let's say I'm I'm
um working with somebody and I'm
prescribing or recommending psilocybin
and I go to recommend that higher
amount, I'm it's going to be on me to
really justify it, to really document my
thinking, etc. And um as I'm thinking
now, I would also really want to know
that they are working with a a
facilitator that I have a relationship
with that I know and trust. And I don't
know if we have a mechanism for that,
but that might make prescribers more
comfortable to um you know to go to that
higher amount. But yeah, at at the end
of the day, I think having just
recommended limits as opposed to hard
limit would probably be best.
>> Thank you, Nathan. Chris, you're next.
Yeah, I just wanted to u correct one
thing. I'm reasonably sure. So, Oregon
did put a limit on it and I know that's
created some some issues for them, but
as far as I know, Colorado has not. And
although their program is pretty um in
its early stages, I I haven't heard of
many
uh negative outcomes as a result of
that.
And then Dominic has a clarifier on
>> Well, I actually have a recommendation.
Um, and what I would recommend is maybe
creating an additional category that is
um other dosage uh as determined by
facilitator or by practitioner. And that
way that would allow for in those uh
special circumstances or situations
where either the individual just on
themselves needs a higher dose due to
tolerance issues or anything else or
other medications. And then uh that way
it would still be within the guidelines
but create a separate category and not
actually fully capping it but still
providing some guidance.
James, you may unmute yourself.
>> Um, I'm in support with Chris and
Dominic and Gregory and the rest of the
group as far as another category is
needed. Um, but I think that category 2
needs to be under review. So, I think
there needs to be a trigger if you are
going higher and above the standard
that's set. Um, there needs to be like a
what I call a per psychedelic
utilization review, right? You need to
have some type of trigger that makes
that facilitator and that clinician
trigger back to the do and say, "Hey,
this is what we did. Here's the
successes. Here's the outcomes." And
hopefully those are positive which I'm
sure they will be because as you guys
know with SSRIs, SNRIs any of the other
medications as well as pharmaccoinetics
and dynamics of each individual person
um as we sit here um those are all going
to be different and so we need the
ranges but we also need safety and we
need a type of utilization review as far
as um like I've said before we need a
board the DO have come up with a group
that sits and reviews these high doses.
is and make sure that the outcomes are
positive because legally they will be
held up very accountable in that space.
If you're practicing above and what you
thought was going to be available or
what you thought was going to work and
it doesn't and so we need to be sure
that that's covered and so that legality
is covered and we need that loop back.
Um but I am in positive favor of of
moving forward with this. Um, but we
need to have a review of it other
category like Dominic said or something
that says that. But you you should be
allowed to have this because of a
blunting or other circumstantial.
Thank you.
>> Gregory, you may unmute yourself.
>> Uh, Ian, just a math
Uh note on high intensity range 22 to 36
MTP that should be 30.6
not 36.
Thank you. I have edited it now and it
was a typo.
Yeah.
Yeah. Cool. Thanks. Just
>> there's just some um notes from the
chat. Kate said mixed feelings about the
cap in the definitions. Yes, some people
need much higher doses and this will be
allowed in any case. On the other hand,
it would be helpful to state what the
usual high dose range is. Chris wrote,
"One more potential language change is
to remove intensity and dosage range as
it is very subjective and based on so
many variables.
All righty. So I have
So
if we added the other dosage
um category, it would be a dosage that's
like not listed or
a dosage that is not listed in the other
categories is used. Then the department
shall review
then it should be permitted under
department review or what are y'all's
thoughts on that
>> Chris?
>> Yeah, I I don't think that that should
be something the department has to
review in every case. I um can't
remember the gentleman's name earlier,
but I think he was on the right track
that you know assuming there if there's
a negative outcome that that would then
be investigated, but it would give the
liberty for the clinician and the
facilitator to work together to to
establish that dose um on their own
perhaps with uh additional screenings or
something would would be um what I would
recommend. Yeah, I was trying to say
like not that they would review it
preemptively, but like after the fact to
um evaluate outcomes. Maybe I didn't use
the right words. Um but thank you. Yeah.
Yeah, that makes sense.
>> James, you may unmute yourself.
>> And I'm with Chris again. And that's
what I was trying to say earlier just to
clarify again was the review would be
conducted by the practitioner, the
facilitator and of course the patient um
and built into their safety plan of
course. And then you basically would
fill out like a a per again a
psychedelic utilization review and then
that would be submitted post
you know to the DOH or to that
reportable and that way we have the data
and the outcome but that would be not
under suggestion you know under the
the practitioner and the facilitator
would have the freedom with that patient
to do that but they would have to just
report post that's I was trying to say
thank you.
>> Jorge wrote in the chat other dosage
psychedelic utilization review. If a
dosage not listed in one of the other
categories is used, the department shall
review
um a high dosage usage.
And Gregory, you can unmute yourself.
I was
I would be interested in including in
the per um
some
metric on EDI like uh
does anyone
in the room have more expertise on EDI
than
that can speak to how that could be
included?
And Ian uh wrote in the chat, "Any
administered dose exceeding the
highintensity dose range shall require a
psychedelic utilization review.
Facilitators and providers shall have
the freedom to use this. However, they
should report to the department on
outcomes.
Sorry. And that was supposed to not be
freedom to use this. It was freedom to
use um the higher dose. However, they
should report to the department on
outcomes. Um
does
so with that other dosage included, does
anyone have anything else we should add?
Uh yeah, sorry if I can if I'm allowed
to finish the Yeah, ego dissolution
inventory. Dominic just put it in there.
Um I think this is really valuable for
research. Um and really understanding
like the potential for education and
research here is very very important and
we can figure out where the efficacy
thresholds for ego dissolution occur.
across
multivariant
human
var like
not just like you know different health
standards or medication profiles but you
know people are just different and we
still don't fully understand why
efficacy of psychedelics is different
from one person to the the next. We have
a lot of ideas, but this could help
define some of that stuff um if we
measure it.
So, are you recommending to have us
check the EDI for um
all dosages or just for the higher one?
I mean, I think all of them honestly,
but especially this this this outside
category when we have like people
requesting something that's just
different. I mean, I think those are
usually the edge cases that lead to the
information that we're trying to get to.
But if we do have a per on every dose
that goes into a database of like state
level research, that would be
great. Give me the keys
to read all that.
>> All righty. And everyone else's thoughts
on the EDI.
Okay. Um, so I can definitely add it to
the other
dosage category. I would feel most
comfortable with that. That way we're
not becoming overly burdensome with what
we are having facilitators do each time.
They're already going to have to do
assessments that are relative to the
respective disorder. So would you be in
support of it for just the other doses?
All
right. If that was directed at me. Yes.
Kate added to the chat, I appreciate the
balance of research and bio bureaucracy.
And Chris gave a thumbs up.
All righty. Well then I think we have
come to
a large part agreement. Um
so I have posted the dosage categories
in the chat. Um
does anyone else have any other points
they would like to bring up? I will give
you guys a little bit to also just
review it. I don't expect you to read at
the speed of light.
All righty. And I see Gregory with his
hand up.
Um, I would just consider changing
should to shall
just to be a little bit
less soft
based if it's a requirement.
But yeah, TBD.
All right. And should has been updated
to shall
All righty. So, I will now turn over to
Nathan.
>> Hey, I'm reading that that section about
other dosage. I'm curious. It seems like
why we're calling out the ego
dissolution inventory in particular. Um,
is it just because we've mentioned that
as one of the things we want to look at?
Is there
Yeah, it feels like that that's that
yeah, that's been called out for some
reason.
>> Um, since it was Gregory's idea, I will
let him speak on it.
Um, my thinking on that is,
uh, back to James and Chris kind of
talked about this need to,
uh,
hit a specific therapeutic target may
require a different dose for people with
um, non-standard
response,
I guess, if that those are the right
words. I feel like I could say that
better. But in so doing that, finding
out like that ego dissolution is that
that kind of primary target. And so
understanding what
um variables that person has, whether
it's SNRIs, whether it's um any other
variable that's causing them to need a
higher dose to get to a target, that
defines the target. and as well as we
can currently
um there is some new science that
includes some EEG stuff that is probably
not accessible for
standard use. Um, but I think just a
simple survey
such as is lined out in the EDI
protocol. Um, which is well established.
Um,
it fairly simple and could help us
understand where that moving target is,
if that makes sense. I got you. That
makes a lot of sense. Thank you.
Dominic.
>> Yeah, thank you, Ian and Greg. uh as you
were talking about that that made me
really think about um you know the the
location for this and I'm wondering if
it shouldn't actually necessarily be in
this aspect of the guidelines but in the
guidelines where uh where we're talking
about the different types of inventories
and assessments that should be utilized
and uh which one should be reported
based on whether it is um uh you know
whether it is um for research purposes
or uh for continuing just with regard to
the patient for their medical care. And
so I'm thinking that it actually because
this is really none of the rest of this
particular document is looking at what
types of assessments should be done. I
sort of feel like while I agree that we
would need to do the EDI, that really
belongs in the assessment aspect of it.
Um, and so I kind of feel like, as
Nathan kind of said, it sort of feels
called out here, but I think that's just
because we haven't done the assessment
aspect, um, and guidance yet. And it
feels like that this should just be in
that section. And so we could include it
as sort of, you know, uh, you know,
pinning it to the board for making sure
it gets included there. But I don't know
that it necessarily should be in this
section. And but I think it should some
be where the language just says right
now shall report to the department on
outcomes. I think that that would be
fine. And then the inclusion of what
types for each category or all
categories then would go under that
assessment and report out.
>> Yeah, that totally um that makes perfect
sense. and like
yeah just define the category as James
said and then Yep.
All right. So with that with that
verbiage strike
which um
are you guys ready for a vote? It
doesn't look like we have much more
conversation.
First, if anyone wants to speak, please
raise your hand.
All right. So, we'll go ahead and move
to a vote. Please uh display the screen
with the voting hand for me.
And to be clear on what we are voting
on, it is this exact language.
with the EDI portion strike, the other
dosage added. Um, but everything else
remained the same.
Oh, and that typo uh correction of
306.
Yeah. Okay. All righty. If you are
voting in affirmation in
support of this document, please raise
your hand at this time.
And it looks like we had 10 hands up.
All right, please put your hands down.
All righty. And then if you are against
this um document, please raise your hand
at this time.
And that is 0 no 104.
The outline of our dose or our dosage
guidelines are adopted.
And
since we already adopted the dosage
definitions,
we can now discuss what would you guys
like to work on at our next meeting or
at the end of finishing up of this one.
Yes.
>> Uh Ian,
this may be handled in a different
committee. I'm not sure, but I I feel
like our preparatory sessions and our
screenings and all of that are going to
be um
involved in this committee. And I think
that might be a logical place to kind of
to start or
>> All right. So yeah, now that we I the
reason I didn't start with preparation
was because I was waiting for um
the patient safety and qualification
committee to finish their um clinical
support tiers because that's going to
determine what we need to check for in
the preparation session. But we could
definitely look at things like um
duration, environment, environmental
conditions. Um
we can also look at risk factors,
contraindications
and side effect profiles associated with
the specific dosage levels. Um but yeah,
that would be a reasonable next step if
we wanted to work on preparation.
Gregory
Um, I don't think I'm going to get a lot
of uh traction behind me, but um
somewhere down the road I would love to
get deep into the conversation of
uh chemotype framework and aligning
specific
uh known combinations of alkyoids
towards unique therapy protocols.
But um I might be alone out here on that
one.
>> I love the idea. My only thing is let's
regulate what
we
have been specifically authorized to
regulate and then we can worry about the
alkyoids cuz we still have to get
everything prepped to
just
>> we do have you know the primary
alkaloids in measure like through the
other we just passed that this morning
like so we'll get
an arugenason.
Um
but yeah, I mean I'm calling from the
future. I'll come back later.
>> Yeah, no worries. So I think the most
important things that we um
get through are administration protocols
and preparation protocols like uh Chris
said. So why don't we accept um
any input on that at this time and then
what we can do is we'll accept public
comment and then at the next meeting we
can really dive deep that way people
have time to you know collect their
resources and sources and that kind of
thing.
How's that sounding to everyone?
All right.
So, and in terms of um administration
and preparation, does anyone have
something they would like to say at this
time or do you guys want to submit the
comments? Um
>> Ian in the chat, James wrote, "Contra
indications and safety plans for
preparation." And Vincent wrote, "Oh,
sorry, moved." Vincent wrote, "I think
starting at preparation would be
appropriate. Thanks for this." And then
Domic um added how people can submit
written public comments in the chat.
>> Perfect. Um yeah, so for the next
meeting, we'll go through um preparation
and administration.
If you guys would like to submit public
comment before um next month, business
day is Monday at 5:00 p.m. That would be
really great for us. Um but when would
you guys like to meet again?
actually. Um,
see if I can find the
it might be unlucky, but Friday the 13th
um, would it be is is looking pretty
free from our end.
>> You know, I might have to try my luck.
Is everyone okay with Friday the 13th at
9:00?
>> Gregory and Chris both have hands up.
>> Uh, Gregory.
>> Um, I just would love
a little elaboration on what you want to
see or hear from us about like
preparation. Like the constraints that I
know we currently have is everything is
ground and homogenized and sold as bulk
or in capsules. So like when we get uh
when a therap like in the administration
point, it's probably going to be in a
capsule most likely or something like
that. Um, are we looking to
put regulation on how an administrator
uh gives a thing to somebody and how
that person ingests it like or like what
specifically would be the most
>> more so like duration um what does the
like what is an environment for
administration look like um because I
know there's been a lot of maybe not
this committee it might been another
one. Um, but of talk of some people like
the idea of an outdoors one. I don't
know that how I feel about that, but
that has been something that has brought
up. So, in terms of administration,
you know, what kind of facility are they
in? What um supports does just a
standard patient need? What um and then
for preparation, you know, what do we
need to screen them for? what do we need
to know if they are on or um take daily?
So questions like that or not questions
concepts that would directly impact you
know how that person is in their
administration session and then how um
we prep them properly. So I've heard
some things that you know prep can be um
tellahalth as long as you show them you
know the room and set and setting that
they are going to be in. Um but you know
each person has a different one and I
genuinely do like reading public
comment. So um I would love to hear what
y'all's ideas on that are. Um
>> yeah so not so much ingestion but
preparation for the experience set and
setting that sort of stuff. Got it.
Yeah. Yeah.
And then Chris,
>> yeah, I just I can't make it on the
13th. I'll be finishing up my
facilitator training in Colorado. Um, so
if we could move it to a different day,
I'd appreciate it. But I understand if
we can I would like to be involved in
this committee though.
>> Um, would the 12th at 9 work for people?
>> Yeah, the the 12th LBA traveling as
well.
I could probably do it from my car.
Oh, and Ian, just from a calendaring
standpoint, uh the 20th we already have
two different meetings, the board
meeting and end of life uh care meeting.
Um so the if you're looking at sticking
on Fridays, the next Friday would be uh
March 27th.
>> I really have no preference for if it's
on Friday or not. Um,
but we could
do we have anything on
March 16th?
>> Uh,
>> I don't see anything. That should be
pretty good.
>> Okay, then. How does everyone feel about
March 16th at um
9,
>> which is a Monday?
Yes,
see some thumbs up. All right. Well,
that sounds uh great. I see no hands of
questions, so I will go ahead and
adjourn. We will meet March 16th at
Monday, March 16th at 9:00 a.m. I look
forward to seeing you guys. Thank you
all so much for your time and
collaboration and taking the time to
read the documents. I really appreciate
all of you. Um other than that, I hope
you guys have a great weekend.
Thank you everybody. We really do
appreciate your participation and it
really helps us to get this program
moving forward and implemented. So on
behalf of the department, thank you. We
did put in the chat for everybody um
just uh the next several upcoming
committee meetings with their
registration links, but if you also
would like to see them uh and get them
as they continue ongoing, the website is
also now in the chat specifically for
that. And so you're welcome to go in and
enjoy uh clicking on the links and
joining meetings.
So thank you everybody.
>> Bye. Thank you.